Force, M. F. (Manning Ferguson), 1824-1899. M. F. Force additional papers, 1845-1900 (MS Am 1862): Guide.
M. F. Force additional papers,
1845-1900 (inclusive),1853-1886 (bulk).
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
MS Am 1862
Force, M. F. (Manning Ferguson), 1824-1899.
6 boxes (3 linear ft.)
Papers of American lawyer, judge, author and officer Manning Ferguson Force, largely concerning his service in the Civil War.
68M-156. Gift of Horton C. Force; received: 1946.
There are no restrictions on physical access to this material. Collection is open for research.
Force was a lawyer and judge in Ohio, an officer in the Union Army during the Civil War, and an author of historical works.
Organized into the following series:
I. Letters by Manning F. Force
II. Letters to Manning F. Force
III. Other letters
IV. Manuscripts
V. Miscellany
Chiefly correspondence, the bulk to Force in his positions as Civil War general and judge; together with letters he wrote to his family, including 88 letters, 1852-1867, to his father, the archivist and historian, Peter Force; diaries, 1861, 1863-1866; and photographs of Civil War soldiers, mostly the men of the 20th Ohio Volunteers, and of family members. Many of the letters are from soldiers who served under him or their dependents, and request recommendations for appointments or pensions; letters from John B. Raymond discuss life in Mississippi during Reconstruction. Also contains a few manuscripts; printed material, mostly papers read before various veterans groups, some by Force; maps; an album of playbills; and clippings.
See also:
M. F. Force Papers (MS AmW 77).
The Rutherford B. Hayes Presidential Center for additional papers of M. F. Force (GA-75).
The Special Collections of the University of Washington for additional papers of M. F. Force.
- I. Letters by Manning F. Force
  - Force, Manning Ferguson, 1824-1899. A.L. (unsigned) to Julius Dexter; Erie County, 23 Dec 1894., (1); 1s. (1p.)
  - Force, Manning Ferguson, 1824-1899. 3 A.L.s. to C. F. Force:
    - Cincinnati, 5 Dec 1849., (2); 1s. (4p.) env.
    - same, 3 Jun 1858., (3); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 8 Jul 1861., (3a); 2s. (5p.) env.
  - Force, Manning Ferguson, 1824-1899. A.L.s. to Hannah (Evans) Force; Cincinnati, 21 Aug 1853., (4); 3s. (10p.)
  - Force, Manning Ferguson, 1824-1899. 2 A.L.s. to Henry C. Force:
    - Cambridge, 25 May 1845., (5); 1s. (4p.)
    - Cincinnati, 30 Jun 1861., (5a); 1s. (1p.)
  - Force, Manning Ferguson, 1824-1899. 88 A.L.s. to Peter Force:
    - Cincinnati, 8 Jul 1852., (5); 1s. (2p.)
      With an A.L.s. from Manning F. Force to Peter Force concerning the donation of books [same place, same date] 1s. (1p.)
    - Cincinnati, 8 May 1853., (7); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 22 May 1853., (8); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 5 Jun 1853., (9); 1s. (2p.)
    - same, 19 Jun 1853., (10); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 3 Jul 1853., (11); 2s. (6p.)
    - same, 17 Jul 1853., (12); 1s. (2p.)
    - same, 9 Oct 1853., (13); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 6 Nov 1853., (14); 1s. (4p.)
    - Newport, 26 Jul 1854., (15); 1s. (4p.)
    - Cincinnati, 10 Sep 1854., (16); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 17 Dec 1854., (17); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 21 Dec 1854., (18); 1s. (1p.)
    - same, 25 Dec 1854., (19); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 31 Dec 1854., (20); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 7 Jan 1855., (21); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 27 Mar 1855., (22); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 8 Oct 1855., (23); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 15 Oct 1855., (24); 1s. (2p.)
    - same, 30 Mar 1856., (25); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 5 Apr 1857., (26); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 10 May 1857., (27); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 17 Jun 1857., (28); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 21 Jun 1857., (29); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 28 Jun 1857., (30); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 14 Jul 1857., (31); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 27 Aug 1857., (32); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 28 Oct 1857., (33); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 31 Jan 1858., (34); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 28 Feb 1858., (35); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 24 May 1858., (36); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 9 Jun 1858., (37); 1s. (2p.)
    - same, 13 Jun 1858., (38); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 3 Apr 1859., (39); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 25 Nov 1859., (40); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 21 Dec 1859., (41); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 3 Jan 1860., (42); 1s. (1p.)
    - same, 3 Jan 1860., (43); 1s. (1p.)
    - same, 4 Jan 1860., (44); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 14 Jan 1860., (45); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 2 Apr 1860., (46); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 26 Apr 1860., (47); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 12 Jun 1860., (48); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 23 Jun 1860., (49); 1s. (2p.)
    - same, 1 Jul 1860., (50); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 9 Aug 1860., (51); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 3 Sep 1860., (52); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 1 Oct 1860., (53); 1s. (2p.)
    - same, 7 Oct 1860., (54); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 22 Dec 1860., (55); 1s. (1p.)
    - same, 18 Feb 1861., (56); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 25 Feb 1861., (57); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 26 Feb 1861., (58); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 1 Apr 1861., (59); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 23 May 1861., (60); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 10 Aug 1861., (61); 1s. (2p.)
    - same, 21 Aug 1861., (62); 1s. (2p.)
    - same, 26 Aug 1861., (63); 1s. (2p.)
    - Camp Chase, 9 Sep 1861., (64); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 21 Sep 1861., (65); 1s. (1p.)
    - same, 15 Oct 1861., (66); 1s. (1p.)
      With a copy of a requisition for army equipment (unidentified hand)
    - Cincinnati, 22 Sep 1864., (67); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 3 Oct 1864., (68); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 28 Jul 1865., (69); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 9 Aug 1865., (70); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 12 Mar 1866., (71); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 30 Apr 1866., (72); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 14 May 1866., (73); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 28 May 1866., (74); 1s. (2p.)
    - same, 4 Jun 1866., (75); 1s. (4p.)
    - Chicago, 1 Jul 1866., (76); 1s. (3p.)
    - Cincinnati, 8 Jul 1866., (77); 1s. (4p.)
    - Owl's Nest, 29 Jul 1866., (78); 1s. (4p.)
    - Cincinnati, 6 Aug 1866., (79); 1s. (4p.)
    - Owl's Nest, 26 Aug 1866., (80); 1s. (4p.)
    - Cincinnati, 10 Sep 1866., (81); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 17 Sep 1866., (82); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 1 Oct 1866., (83); 1s. (4p.)
    - Boston, 14 Oct 1866., (84); 1s. (4p.)
    - Cincinnati, 21 Oct 1866., (85); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 29 Oct 1866., (86); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 19 Nov 1866., (87); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 20 Jan 1867., (88); 1s. (1p.)
    - same, 7 Oct 1867., (89); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 15 Nov 1867., (90); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 25 Nov 1867., (91); 1s. (2p.)
    - same, 8 Dec 1867., (92); 1s. (4p.)
  - Force, Manning Ferguson, 1824-1899. A.L.s. to Caroline C. Marsh; Pomeroy, 6 Aug 1882., (93); 1s. (4p.)
  - Force, Manning Ferguson, 1824-1899. A.L.s. to Douglas Putnam; Cincinnati, 27 Jun 1884., (94); 1s. (1p.)
  - Force, Manning Ferguson, 1824-1899. A.L.s. to John Sherman; Cincinnati, 12 Feb 1868., (95); 1s. (1p.)
  - Force, Manning Ferguson, 1824-1899. A.L. (unsigned) to the U.S. Dept. of War; Cincinnati, 28 Aug 1866., (96); 1s. (2p.)
- II. Letters to Manning F. Force
  - Adam, G. Gordon. A.L.s.; Vicksburg, 18 May 1871., (97); 1s. (1p.)
  - Adams, Noah T. A.L.s.; Camden, 22 Jan 1872., (98); 1s. (2p.)
  - Adams, S. L. A.L.s.; Napoleon, 1 Jun 1868., (99); 1s. (2p.)
  - Adams, Samuel R. 8 A.L.s.:
    - Napoleon, 3 Mar 1866., (100); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 29 Jun 1866., (101); 2s. (4p.)
    - Camden, 21 Jul 1867., (102); 1s. (4p.)
    - same, 5 Jan 1868., (103); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 28 Jul 1868., (104); 2s. (7p.)
    - same, 3 Oct 1875., (105); 2s. (4p.) env.
    - same, 17 May 1880., (106); 2s. (3p.) env.
    - same, 5 Jun 1880., (107); 1s. (2p.)
  - Anderson, Thomas McArthur, 1836-1917. A.L.s.; Laredo, 14 Oct 1869., (108); 1s. (3p.)
  - Andrews, Israel Ward, 1815-1888. A.L.s.; Marietta College, 21 Jun 1882., (109); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. A.L.s.; Washington, 3 May 1866., (110); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Beaty, Peter. 4 A.L.s.:
    - Van Wert, 17 Mar 1868., (111); 1s. (2p.) env.
    - same, 1 Aug 1868., (112); 1s. (1p.) env.
    - Vestaburg, 12 Feb 1880., (113); 1s. (2p.) env.
    - same, 24 Feb 1880., (114); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Belknap, William Worth, 1829-1890. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Keokuk, 24 Aug 1867., (115); 1s. (1p.)
    - Washington, 13 May 1871., (116); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Bishop, John Soast, 1834-1915. A.L.s.; Indianapolis, 10 Apr 1866., (117); 1s. (1p.)
  - Bliss, Eugene Frederick, 1836- 2 T.L.s.:
    - Cincinnati, 15 Jan 1895., (118); 2s. (2p.)
    - same, 5 Mar 1899., (119); 3s. (3p.)
  - Bradley, Daniel. A.L.s.; Red Oak, 5 Dec 1869., (120); 1s. (2p.)
  - Brecht, Albert. A.L.s.; Columbus, 5 Sep 1882., (121); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Breckinridge, S. M. 3 A.L.s.:
    - St. Louis, 4 Jul 1877., (122); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 3 Sep 1877., (123); 1s. (2p.)
    - same, 13 Sep 1877., (124); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Brinkerhoff, Henry R. A.L.s.; Kansas City, 27 May 1867., (125); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Bryant, George E. 2 A.L.s.:
    - East Point, 18 Sep 1864., (126); 1s. (1p.) env.
    - Madison, 5 Jun 1879., (127); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Buckland, R. P. A.L.s.; Fremont, 12 Apr 1879., (128); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Carns, John P. A.L.s.; Vicksburg, 23 Aug 1866., (129); 1s. (3p.)
  - Case, Charles. A.L.s.; Waukegan, 28 Apr 1867., (130); 1s. (1p.)
  - Colby, George W. A.L.s.; Detroit, 10 Feb 1868., (131); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Conse, L. D. A.L.s.; Withamsville, 4 Nov 1869., (132); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Corbin, H. C. A.L.s.; Washington, 3 Apr 1861., (133); 1s. (1p.)
  - Corwin, [Mrs.] Levi J. A.L.s.; Delaware, 29 May 1882., (134); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Craig, Joseph. A.L.s.; Canton, 23 Mar 1880., (135); 1s. (3p.) env.
  - Curren, Joseph F. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Delaware, 24 Feb 1869., (136); 1s. (3p.)
      With a MS. note in the hand of Manning F. Force.
    - Delaware, 8 Sep 1871., (137); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Davis, Theodore R. A.L.s.; Asbury Park, 12 Apr 1886., (138); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Dawes, William G. A.L.s.; Ipswich, 3 Jan 1887., (139); 1s. (3p.) env.
  - Dennison, William, 1815-1882. A.L.s.; Columbus, 20 Apr 1880., (140); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Dexter, Julius, 1840-1898. A.L.s.; Cincinnati, 28 Dec 1894., (141); 1s. (2p.)
  - Dudley, L. E. A.L.s.; New York, 4 Oct 1872., (142); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Dunmeyer, G. W. A.L.s.; Lima, 10 Aug 1868., (143); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Durbin, R. C. A.L.s.; Napoleon, 30 Dec 1870., (144); 1s. (2p.)
  - Dusey, Edward. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Westerville, 18 Sep 1884., (145); 2s. (4p.) env.
    - same, 11 Jul 1885., (146); 1s. (2p.)
  - Dwight, Henry O. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Northampton, 24 Oct 1867., (147); 1s. (3p.)
    - Constantinople, 20 Dec 1870., (148); 1s. (4p.) env.
  - Edmonds, I. E. A.L.s.; Bolivar Landing, 23 Jun 1867., (149); 1s. (3p.)
  - Eliot, Charles William, 1834-1926. 5 A.L.s.:
    - Cambridge, 5 Mar 1872., (150); 1s. (2p.) env.
    - same, 24 May 1876., (151); 1s. (2p.)
    - same, 30 Jan 1878., (152); 1s. (3p.)
    - same, 15 Apr 1878., (153); 1s. (2p.)
    - same, 8 Dec 1882., (154); 2s. (4p.)
  - Elliott, Charles W. 3 A.L.s.:
    - New York, 2 May 1871., (155); 1s. (3p.) env.
    - Cambridge, 5 Jan [1872?], (156); 1s. (2p.)
    - same, 27 Feb [1872?], (157); 1s. (1p.)
  - Elmes, Webster. A.L.s.; Washington, 16 Nov 1871., (158); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Eskridge, James. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Winamac, 30 Apr 1882., (159); 1s. (1p.) env.
    - same, 6 Aug 1882., (160); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Ewing, Thomas. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Lancaster, 29 Oct 1867., (161); 1s. (1p.)
    - Cincinnati, 17 Jan 1874., (162); 1s. (2p.)
  - Fernandez Duro, Cesáreo, 1830-1908. A.L.s.; Madrid, 14 Dec 1885., (163); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Fleming, James A. A.L.s.; Indianapolis, 13 Feb 1872., (164); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Foraker, Joseph Benson, 1846-1917. 3 letters:
    - A.L.s.; Gettysburg, 30 Apr 1882., (165); 5s. (9p.) env.
    - Foraker, Joseph Benson, 1846-1917. MS.L.s.; Cincinnati, 12 Oct 1883., (166); 1s. (1p.)
    - Foraker, Joseph Benson, 1846-1917. MS.L.s.; Columbus, 12 Nov 1887., (167); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Forbes, Archibald, 1838-1900. A.L.s.; Burlington, 10 Mar 1882., (168); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Force, A. B. 3 A.L.s.:
    - Erie, 23 Feb 1871., (169); 1s. (2p.) env.
    - Erie, 21 Oct 1871., (170); 1s. (2p.)
    - Erie, 9 Aug 1876., (171); 2s. (2p.)
  - Force, F. H. A.L.s.; Cincinnati, 21 Feb 1872., (172); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Force, Kathryn. 2 A.L.s.:
    - [At-home] 8 Dec 1876., (173); 1s. (3p.)
    - Carthage, 29 Jan 1877., (174); 1s. (4p.) env.
  - Freeman, Sarah W. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Grafton, 17 Aug 1876., (175); 1s. (3p.) env.
    - Grafton, 12 Sep [1876], (176); 1s. (3p.) env.
  - Fry, Florence. 5 A.L.s.:
    - Holton, 29 Oct 1871., (177); 1s. (2p.)
    - Carbondale, 26 Jun 1872., (178); 1s. (1p.)
    - Carbondale, 10 Jul 1872., (179); 1s. (2p.)
    - Abilene, 15 Dec 1872., (180); 1s. (2p.) env.
    - Carlton, 25 Oct 1875., (181); 1s. (2p.)
  - Fry, John D. 6 A.L.s.:
    - Lexington, 16 Jan 1870., (182); 1s. (2p.)
    - Richmond, 9 Oct 1870., (183); 1s. (4p.)
    - Carbondale, 11 Mar 1872., (184); 1s. (2p.)
    - Carlton, 6 Feb 1874., (185); 1s. (2p.)
    - Carlton, 4 Jan 1880., (186); 1s. (3p.) env.
    - Abilene, 4 Nov [n.d.], (187); 1s. (2p.)
  - Fry, Manning Force. A.L.s.; Carlton, 23 Dec 1879., (188); 1s. (2p.)
  - Fuller, John W. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Toledo, 1 Mar 1871., (189); 1s. (1p.) env.
    - Toledo, 12 Apr 1882., (190); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Garfield, Lucretia Rudolph, 1832-1918. A.L.s.; Cleveland, 12 Mar 1884., (191); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Glasgow, E. A.L.s.; Shiloh, 6 Dec 1886., (192); 2s. (6p.) env.
  - Goodbrake, Christopher. A.L.s.; Clinton, 25 May 1882., (193); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Goodhart, William. A.L.s.; Newton Falls, 24 Mar [n.d.], (194); 1s. (4p.) env.
  - Goodman, Alfred Thomas, 1845-1871. 2 letters:
    - A.L.s.; Cleveland, 6 Jan 1870., (195); 1s. (1p.)
    - Goodman, Alfred Thomas, 1845-1871. MS.L.s.; Cleveland, 12 Nov 1870., (196); 1s. (1p.)
  - Grant, Ulysses Simpson, 1822-1885. A.L.s.; New York, 13 Feb 1881., (197); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Gray, Horace, 1828-1902. 6 A.L.s.:
    - Boston, 25 May 1868., (198); 1s. (2p.)
    - Boston, Jun 1868., (199); 1s. (1p.)
    - Boston, 5 Apr 1870., (200); 1s. (3p.)
    - Boston, 11 Jan 1872., (201); 1s. (4p.) env.
    - Boston, 12 Feb 1875., (202); 1s. (4p.)
    - Boston, 17 Jan 1880., (203); 1s. (3p.) env.
  - Greer, S. W. A.L.s.; Eddyville, 12 Jun 1882., (204); 1s. (4p.) env.
  - Gregg, R. B. A.L.s.; Coloma, 4 May 1881., (205); 1s. (4p.) env.
  - Groesbeck, William Slocum, 1815-1897. A.L.s.; Cincinnati, 27 Mar [n.d.], (206); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Guild, E. Q. A.L.s.; Brookline, 13 Sep 1874., (207); 1s. (4p.) env.
  - Halstead, Murat, 1829-1908. 2 letters:
    - A.L.s.; Cincinnati, 29 Dec 1874., (208); 1s. (3p.) env.
    - MS.L.s.; Cincinnati, 2 Jan 1875., (209); 1s. (3p.)
  - Hamilton, Schuyler, 1822- A.L.s.; Jamaica, 15 Dec 1881., (210); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Harmon, Judson, 1846-1927. A.L.s.; Cincinnati, 26 Jun 1884., (211); 1s. (1p.)
  - Harrison, I. W. A.L.s.; Anderson, 28 Jul 1868., (212); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Hatch, Edward. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Santa Fe, 8 Nov 1880., (213); 1s. (2p.)
    - Fort Leavenworth, 18 Jun 1882., (214); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Hazen, William Babcock, 1830-1887. A.L.s.; Buford, 1 May 1880., (215); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Hemstreet, William. A.L.s.; Brooklyn, 24 Feb 1871., (216); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Hill, Edward L. A.L.s.; Oxford, 27 Mar 1871., (217); 1s. (3p.) env.
  - Hills, V. T. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Delaware, 8 Jul 1871., (218); 1s. (2p.)
    - Delaware, 31 Dec 1874., (219); 1s. (2p.)
  - Hissong, S. J. A.L.s.; Van Buren, 3 May 1867., (220); 1s. (2p.)
  - Hitchcock, Peter M. 4 A.L.s.:
    - Cleveland, 6 Sep 1866., (221); 1s. (1p.)
    - Cleveland, 22 Apr 1871., (222); 1s. (1p.)
    - Cleveland, 9 Dec 1871., (223); 1s. (2p.) env.
    - Cleveland, 19 May 1881., (224); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Horsford, Eben Norton, 1818-1893. A.L.s.; Cambridge, 15 Oct 1872., (225); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Hughes, Thomas, 1822-1896. A.L.s.; [Charing-Cross] 8 Nov 1871., (226); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Hunt, Ira D. A.L.s.; Sparta, Ohio, 11 Oct 1875., (227); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Hunt, R. C. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Mt. Vernon, 5 Jan 1875., (228); 1s. (3p.) env.
    - Hunts Station, [n.d.], (229); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - James, Charles Pinckney, 1818-1899. 3 A.L.s.:
    - Washington, 1 Aug 1866., (230); 1s. (3p.)
    - Washington, 22 Oct 1866., (231); 1s. (3p.)
    - Washington, 18 May 1872., (232); 1s. (4p.) env.
  - John, Lewis A. 3 A.L.s.:
    - Reading, 12 Nov 1872., (233); 1s. (4p.) env.
    - Reading, 29 Nov 1872., (234); 1s. (2p.)
    - Dunlap, 10 Feb 1880., (235); 1s. (3p.) env.
  - John, [Mrs.] Lewis A. A.L.s.; Dunlap, May 1886., (236); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Johnson, W. W. A.L.s.; Ironton, 8 Oct 1877., (237); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Kaga, A. A.L.s.; Houston, 28 Jul 1873., (238); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Kinney, William H. A.L.s.; Fredericktown, 1 Jun 1880., (239); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Knots, Daniel. A.L.s.; West Austintown, 16 Mar 1879., (240); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Koch, Charles E. A.L.s.; Chicago, 8 Dec 1873., (241); 1s. (4p.) env.
  - Kwapp, James. MS.L. (in the hand of Linly Kwapp); Sidney, 25 Feb 1871., (242); 1s. (4p.) env.
  - Leaty, Axel. A.L.s.; Wisby, Sweden, 30 Oct 1877., (243); 1s. (3p.) env.
  - Leggett, Mortimer Dormer, 1831-1896. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Cleveland, 2 Jan 1883., (244); 1s. (4p.) env.
    - Cleveland, 3 Jan 1883., (245); 1s. (3p.)
  - [Lenros?], J. A.L.s.; New York, 17 Jan 1883., (246); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Letcher, Daniel, d. 1872. 4 A.L.s.:
    - Vicksburgh, 4 Dec 1870., (247); 1s. (2p.) env.
    - St. Joseph, 23 Jan 1871., (248); 1s. (2p.)
    - Crimea, 19 Mar 1872., (249); 1s. (1p.)
    - [n.p., n.d.], (250); 1s. (1p.)
  - [Ley?], Alfred E. A.L.s.; Delaware, 17 May 1870., (251); 1s. (1p.)
  - Linsted, Daniel B. A.L.s.; Cassville, 15 Dec 1868., (252); 1s. (2p.)
    With an MS. note (in the hand of Manning F. Force) on the first page.
  - Lockwood, E. E. A.L.s.; Utica, 6 Jun 1880., (253); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Loewenstein, Emil. A.L.s.; Danzig, 10 Oct 1870., (254); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Longwell, Norton T. 7 A.L.s.:
    - Kilbourne, 10 Feb 1867., (255); 1s. (3p.)
    - [n.p.] 9 Jul 1871., (256); 1s. (2p.)
    - Edin, 4 Dec 1871., (257); 1s. (2p.)
    - [n.p.] 7 Apr 1872., (258); 1s. (3p.)
    - [n.p.] 9 May 1872., (259); 1s. (2p.)
    - [Kilbourne] 20 May 1872., (260); 1s. (2p.) env.
    - [n.p.] 5 Jan 1874., (261); 1s. (2p.)
  - Longworth, Joseph. A.L.s.; Cincinnati, 10 May 1879., (262); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Lord, Catharine W. A.L.s.; Cincinnati, 7 Jun 1895., (263); 4s. (4p.) env.
  - Lucas, A. J. A.L.s.; Summerfield, 6 Jan 1880., (264); 1s. (3p.) env.
  - Lupton, James. A.L.s.; Washington, 10 Nov 1866., (265); 1s. (1p.) env.
    With a photograph of Civil War soldiers on Lookout Mountain.
  - Lyburger, E. L. A.L.s.; Mt. Vernon, 17 May 1866., (266); 1s. (2p.)
  - McCracken, W. W. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Mt. Gilead, 4 Nov 1867., (267); 1s. (2p.) env.
    - Mt. Gilead, 9 Nov 1867., (268); 1s. (2p.)
  - Mace, Hiram. A.L.s.; Convoy, 24 Oct 1882., (269); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - McElroy, C. H. 3 A.L.s.:
    - Delaware, 15 Mar 1867., (270); 1s. (2p.)
    - Delaware, 24 Mar 1871., (271); 1s. (2p.)
    - Delaware, 20 Dec 1882., (272); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - McElroy, J. N. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Fort Ellsworth, 26 Jun 1866., (273); 1s. (3p.)
    - Fort Ellsworth, 2 Nov 1866., (274); 1s. (3p.)
  - Mackenzie, Ranald Slidell, 1840-1889. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Santa Fe, 3 Oct 1882., (275); 1s. (3p.) env.
    - Santa Fe, 5 Nov 1882., (276); 1s. (2p.)
  - Manson, W. C. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Mount Vernon, 24 Feb 1869., (277); 1s. (2p.)
    - Sparta, Ohio, 18 Apr 1870., (278); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Marks, Isaac. A.L.s.; Austin, 12 Apr 1871., (279); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Marsh, Caroline (Crane), 1816-1901. A.L.s.; Vallombrosa, 28 Aug 1882., (280); 1s. (4p.) env.
  - Marsh, George Perkins, 1801-1882. 2 letters:
    - A.L.s.; Florence, 21 Oct 1871., (281); 1s. (1p.)
    - MS.L.s. (in the hand of Caroline (Crane) Marsh); Rome, 29 Nov 1881., (282); 1s. (4p.)
  - Matthews, Stanley, 1824-1889. A.L.s.; Washington, 23 Mar 1882., (283); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Merrill, J. W. A.L.s.; Missouri Valley, 15 Jan 1873., (284); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Morgan, John Tyler, 1824-1907. A.L.s.; Selma, 21 Jan 1878., (285); 1s. (2p.)
  - Munson, Gilbert D. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Zanesville, 15 Nov 1881., (286); 6s. (6p.)
    - Zanesville, 26 Jan 1887., (287); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Nelson, Frank Eden. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Delaware, 6 Jun 1872., (288); 1s. (2p.) env.
    - [n.p., n.d.], (289); 1s. (1p.)
  - Nickerson, H. W. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Marietta, 28 Feb 1882., (290); 1s. (1p.)
    - Marietta, 21 Jun 1882., (291); 2s. (2p.)
  - Noah, H. A.L.s.; Columbia, 2 Jan 1872., (292); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Nogle, William H. A.L.s.; Alpha, 7 Apr 1873., (293); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Noyes, Edward Follansbee, 1832-1890. A.L.s.; Cincinnati, 2 Dec 1882., (294); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Oldseyd, O. H. A.L.s.; Columbus, 15 May 1867., (295); 1s. (2p.)
  - Ott, Emanuel. A.L.s.; Wigginsport, 16 Sep 1876., (296); 1s. (2p.)
  - Owen, Selwyn N. A.L.s.; Columbus, 17 Jun 1885., (297); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Palmer, James J. A.L.s.; Cherry Valley, 11 Apr 1866., (298); 1s. (1p.)
  - Patchin, A. P. A.L.s.; Oswego, 25 Jun [n.d.], (299); 1s. (2p.)
  - Pearson, Robert N. A.L.s.; Springfield, 13 Mar 1869., (300); 1s. (4p.)
  - Pener, Benjamin. A.L.s.; Cincinnati, 23 [ ] 1885., (301); 1s. (1p.)
  - Perkins, Charles Elliot, 1840-1907. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Washington, 19 Feb 1877., (302); 2s. (8p.)
    - Burlington, 10 Mar 1877., (303); 1s. (4p.) env.
  - Pherlea, E. A. A.L.s.; Columbus, 23 Jun 1866., (304); 1s. (1p.)
  - Porter, G. W. A.L.s.; Clinton, 18 Oct 1872., (305); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Potts, Benjamin Franklin, 1836-1887. A.L.s.; Helena, 27 Mar 1877., (306); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Pringle, Edward J. 4 A.L.s.:
    - San Francisco, 27 Oct 1883., (307); 2s. (4p.)
    - San Francisco, 6 Dec 1885., (308); 1s. (2p.)
    - San Francisco, 10 Dec 1885., (309); 1s. (2p.) env.
    - San Francisco, 2 Jan 1887., (310); 1s. (2p.)
  - Putnam, Douglas. A.L.s.; Marietta, 28 Jun 1884., (311); 1s. (1p.)
  - Quincy, Eliza Susan, 1798-1884. 11 A.L.s.:
    - Quincy, 14 Aug 1864., (312); 1s. (4p.)
    - Boston, 21 Nov 1870., (313); 1s. (4p.)
    - Boston, 8 May 1875., (314); 1s. (4p.)
    - Quincy, 10 Jul 1876., (315); 1s. (4p.)
    - Quincy, 12 Mar 1877., (316); 1s. (4p.)
    - Quincy, 23 Apr 1881., (317); 1s. (4p.)
    - Quincy, 15 Aug 1881., (318); 1s. (2p.)
    - Quincy, 14 Dec 1881., (319); 1s. (2p.)
    - Quincy, 27 Feb 1882., (320); 1s. (2p.)
    - Quincy, 4 Jan 1883., (321); 1s. (2p.)
    - [n.p., n.d.], (322); 1s. (4p.)
  - Ray, D. Gano. A.L.s.; Boulagne-sur-mer, 21 Sep 1871., (323); 1s. (4p.) env.
  - Raymond, John B. 26 A.L.s.:
    - Willerton Plantation, 24 Oct 1866., (324); 1s. (2p.)
    - Vicksburg, 26 Jul 1867., (325); 1s. (2p.)
    - Vicksburg, 5 Oct 1867., (326); 1s. (4p.)
    - Vicksburg, 9 Oct 1867., (327); 1s. (2p.) env.
    - Vicksburg, 2 Dec 1867., (328); 1s. (3p.) env.
    - Jackson, 23 Mar 1871., (329); 2s. (3p.) env.
    - Jackson, 12 Apr 1871., (330); 1s. (1p.) env.
    - Jackson, 28 Jun 1871., (331); 1s. (2p.)
    - Jackson, 2 Dec 1871., (332); 1s. (2p.) env.
    - Jackson, 30 Dec 1871., (333); 2s. (4p.) env.
    - Jackson, 8 Dec 1873., (334); 1s. (4p.) env.
    - Jackson, 17 Aug 1875., (335); 3s. (3p.) env.
    - Jackson, 19 Mar 1876., (336); 3s. (3p.)
    - Washington, 18 Feb 1877., (337); 1s. (1p.)
    - Washington, 27 Feb 1877., (338); 6s. (6p.)
    - Cleveland, 28 May 1877., (339); 1s. (3p.)
    - Cleveland, 5 Jul 1877., (340); 2s. (8p.)
    - Washington, 7 Jul 1877., (341); 2s. (8p.)
    - Washington, 23 Jul 1877., (342); 1s. (4p.) env.
    - Yaukton, 4 Aug 1877., (343); 2s. (2p.) env.
    - Deadwood, 21 Jan 1878., (344); 1s. (4p.) env.
    - Washington, 2 Mar 1878., (345); 1s. (4p.)
    - Yaukton, 15 Mar 1878., (346); 1s. (2p.)
    - Rapid City, 17 Jun 1878., (347); 5s. (5p.) env.
    - Fargo, 28 Nov 1882., (348); 4s. (4p.) env.
    - Willerton, 29 Apr [n.d.], (349); 2s. (4p.)
  - Read, T. Bueleman. A.L.s.; Rome, 1 Dec 1869., (350); 2s. (4p.) env.
  - Reynolds, Thomas. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Madison, 29 Mar 1871., (351); 1s. (1p.) env.
    - Madison, 17 Aug 1872., (352); 1s. (1p.) env.